

Alex Woodman

Full Stack Developer, UX Enthusiast alexthegoodman@gmail.com 616.325.5407 Grand Rapids, MI

Summary

I am passionate about user experience and the development that brings it to life

Since I was just a boy in elementary school, I've been creating interfaces. Nowadays, I serve clients on the web and on mobile to overcome business obstacles and satisfy target segments.

Portfolio: alexthegoodman.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alexthegoodman/ **GitHub**: github.com/alexthegoodman

Qualifications

- Semantic Markup
- SASS / CSS processors
- FE JavaScript ES7+ (jQuery, React, React Native, Gulp, TypeScript, Angular, AngularJS)
- BE JavaScript (Node, Express, SSR, Babel, Webpack, NPM, Yarn, CRUD, logging, error handling, style guides)
- BE PHP (WordPress Plugins, Craft Plugins)
- Custom CMS (Craft CMS, ExpressionEngine, WordPress)
- New Technologies (Variable Fonts, CSS Grid, LoopBack 4, etc)
- DevOps, QA Processes, GIT, Pipelines, CI / CD, Automated Unit, Integrated, and UI Testing
- Development Tools (VS Code, WebStorm, Terminal, XCode)
- Collaboration Tools (Atlassian Suite, Github, GitLab, Asana, Trello, Slack)
- Design Tools (Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InVision)
- Infrastructure Tools (Heroku, AWS S₃ and RDS)

Featured Work

Web and Mobile Applications

Reeviewr

2019.reeviewr.com

Assets for iOS, Apple TV, and Web assetsbeta.com

HomScout Beta leadscoutapp.com

Web Sites

Baumann Building baumannbuilding.com

ClimateGuys.com climateguys.com

For His Glory ammiebouwman.com

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

January 2013 to Now

Identify and obtain all business information for the challenge at hand Develop specifications and requirements for projects
Implement verifiable quality assurance controls
Deliver projects which meet or exceed scope requirements
Provide long-term support mechanisms and procedures

EDUStaff

March 2018 to Now

Collaborate closely with other developers throughout planning, deliberation, and production stages

Develop front-end features according to best-practices

Develop unit tests intended for CI pipelines and deployment systems

Employ new Web APIs, browser features, syntax optimizations and standardization

Cull Group

October 2015 to June 2016

Translate Photoshop and Sketch designs and wireframes to standards-compliant, mobile-responsive, backwards-compatible pages Integrate pages with ExpressionEngine CMS and enable control of content pieces, meta data and other items

Develop email newsletters and transactional email notifications which work through a variety of email clients (including Outlook) and integrate with the CMS Enjoyed the chance to experiment with a Canvas-based Bejeweled-style game for mobile devices

Thinkbox Creative

February 2014 to January 2015

Collaborate closely with designers and project managers to ensure timely completion of all deliverables

Translate Photoshop designs to standards-compliant, mobile-responsive, backwards-compatible pages

Integrate pages with WordPress CMS and enable control of content pieces, layout, meta data and other items

Other early experiences included Givinci, WebLeap, and ReadabilityHub.

I am self-taught. I have a Feedly composed of GitHub Releases feeds, and I continue to read as much as I can.